My son sacrificed his life to save me
these powers are not a gift but a curse
born out of rage
this loose cannon needs to be locked down
before innocent people start getting hurt
he's been asleep for 5 000 years
you find us a cell that can hold them we'll
take care of the rest who's on the team
i didn't bring a passport we don't need passports
we're the justice society
here we go
or you can be its savior
Welcome back everyone it's charlie this will be
my new black adam trailer video there's a whole
bunch of easter eggs here connecting it to the
other dc eu movies so we'll break it all down
if you're brand new to the channel be sure to
subscribe to get all the videos they're also
having a big disney plus day this weekend with
a bunch of marvel trailers probably some star
wars trailers i'll be doing videos for all that
stuff as well too the big thing in this trailer
is revealing the actual main villain of the film
like black adam is the anti-hero of the film so
you have to have somebody in the movie that's
even worse for him to go up against eventually
and that's going to be the sabac character from
the shazam comics they also show you a bunch more
of the justice society in their mansion from
the comics it's like an upgraded version that
you imagine that they would do in live action we
saw some interiors of it briefly in the previous
trailers but now we get like the full shot and
they kind of do the x-men thing in the original
x-men films where literally like the yard opens up
to an actual hangar bay it gave me classic x-men
vibes with the x-jet coming out of the basketball
court the other big thing here too we find is that
amanda waller has a big cameo scene it's meant to
take place after the events of the suicide squad
movie in peacemaker but she's the person that
calls the justice society to go take care of black
adam when people find out that he's come back
so the whole idea is that she's not sending them
to take care of sabach like that hasn't become a
thing yet inner gang seems like they're trying to
resurrect spock and use his powers it sounds like
at the beginning of the movie they unwittingly
unleash black adam like adriana tomas's
character unleashes him using this spell here
then amanda waller finds out about it at argus and
she calls the justice society to take care of it
they do probably have a reason for amanda waller
not calling the justice league and it's probably
because they don't want to have anything to do
with her like in the past we saw her have most
of her dealings with batman but even with all the
craziness that's happening in the flash movie in
the flashpoint storyline that they're doing like
they're messing a little bit with the timeline
after the fact amanda waller is so shady batman
probably doesn't want to have anything to do
with her and the other justice league characters
wouldn't either like superman wouldn't want to
deal with amanda waller the rock has been hyping
up black adam versus superman in the future and
there is supposed to be some kind of henry cavill
superman cameo scene at the end the same way that
he had a cameo scene at the end of the first
shazam movie but the way the rock explained it
is that after black adam gets released from his
prison he's been gone for five thousand years so
he comes out not knowing anything about any of
the justice league characters he might know a
little bit about wonder woman in the amazonians
but that'd probably be it there is this whole
sequence where amanda waller talks about actually
capturing black adam and holding him in a prison
then you see all these scenes seemingly a
black adam without his powers wearing his
ancient clothing from kondok stuck underwater and
that might be how they capture him like somehow he
might say his power word which is shazam like the
shazam characters which deactivates his abilities
but the big thing in the comics is that he rarely
rarely does this like he never wants to turn his
powers off like usually if that happens someone
tricks him into doing it because this is meant
to be black adam held in prison without his powers
he looks way less swole than this version of black
adam they might just be playing it this way for
a big reveal when he says his power word again
activating his powers and bursts out in this huge
explosion making it a big wtf moment in the movie
but i think the whole idea is then presenting
the choice to him whether or not he's going to
actually help them or if he's just going to ignore
the problem and do his own thing and try to take
over kondok when dr fate is talking about choosing
different paths the whole idea with his character
is that one of his abilities in the movie at least
is that he has seen visions of the future and he's
basically talking about this apocalypse and he's
not talking about the one that we see during
the justice league snyder cut because that's
also an apocalypse of a very different kind
make all the dark side apocalypse references
you want because apocalypse and apocalypse
two completely different ideas but you do see the
similarity in the name of the apocalypse planet to
the actual idea of destruction apocalypse usually
in the comics they play in this way like very dark
anti-hero he'll usually work against the heroes
a lot of times but then eventually when the chips
are dead like when is really needed he will help
them out begrudgingly i think that's one of the
other reasons why they included hawkman instead
of hog girl during the movie because either one
would work just based on the explainer here the
fact that they resurrect they would still be alive
in present day because they want you to identify
more with this hardcore mindset and hawkman is
way way more hardcore in the comics than hot girl
usually he's the guy that you have to stop from
wrecking everything in sight and that's kind of
the same vibe with black adam during the movie
he just wants to mow through everybody that's in
his way i'll explain the differences between the
justice society of the dcu and what they've been
doing this whole time like in the timeline of the
dc eu while the justice league has been operating
because within the context of the dceu movies with
the exception of the wonder woman movie which
obviously takes place in the distant past most
of what happens with the justice league forming
actually happens relatively close to present day
in the version of the justice society that we
meet at the beginning of the movie is hawkman
and dr fate and they're like the remnants of an
older team that mostly died off through the course
of their adventures and they're the two ones
that have just survived to present day and they
reformed the team with cyclone and adam smasher
the new young people the big thing with the sabog
villain that's similar to the shazam characters is
that just like the gods that give shazam and black
adam their powers like their names are acronyms
they get their powers from different gods the
title of the shazam movie is literally fury of the
gods and it's all about the daughters of atlas one
of the gods that gives shazam his powers trying to
take the power back for themselves obviously black
adam is connected to the shazam movies even though
they're not going to have like a giant crossover
for at least a couple more movies you can see how
they're trying to make a lot of the easter eggs
and connections and the lore in both of the movies
line up with each other so that when they do cross
over everything makes sense like the timeline
will make sense the sabak villain is kind of
like a demon that does the same thing as the gods
that the shazam characters get their powers from
he can grant people powers of the same way but
what might be happening in the movie is that
either he himself finds a way to walk the planet
and wants to just take it over himself or he picks
an avatar and just takes over their body and then
tries to take over the world one of the other big
changes that some of you may have noticed in this
trailer from the previous ones is that they've
completely changed the color correction so all the
footage doesn't have this weird orange cast to it
they also added some subtitles to black adam
when he's speaking to them in kondok like he's
using the kondok language when he's talking
to these other mercenaries taking them out
your magic is weak when they're trying to kill
him with the bullets the voice over from the woman
in the trailer taking the black adam for test
calling him on his bullcrap like you're only here
for revenge you don't want to do anything good
that's probably adriana tomasz's character and
she's probably the one that brings him around on
actually helping them out by the end of the movie
because she and her little brother are meant to
remind him of his former wife and son who died in
the past if you haven't read the comics there's a
long time romance between adriana tomas and black
adam in present day they become lovers and he
grants some of his power to her there's like a
whole story line i don't know if they're going to
do any of that in the movies maybe they do sequels
i don't think we'll see that during this movie
they kind of just use that idea during thor love
and thunder with thor sharing his power with other
people but that is basically what shazam does in
the shazam movies and you see it more during the
shazam 2 trailer the whole idea that he shared his
power with the rest of the family so even though
each one is weaker by default just because he's
shared a certain amount of power with them when
they're able to work together they're much more
effective in a fight than like a single person
like black adam that's why when they fight him
the only times they're usually able to defeat
him is when they all work together at the same
time but part of the comedy of the shazam movies
like obviously the tone is very different from the
black adam movie is that they're still kind
of learning how to do that but i think when
we get to the events of shazam too the family
has spent a little bit more time working with
their powers and they've got at least a little bit
better as for all the big changes at dc right now
like there's this new 10-year plan they're still
looking for their kevin feige reportedly they
almost found someone named dan lin who had worked
at some of the previous dc movies like he actually
worked on the george miller version of the justice
league movie back during the early 2000s when
that was still a thing reportedly that deal fell
through and dc warner brothers are still looking
for their kevin feige person so we'll find out
who that is sometime in the next six months or so
i don't think they've formally announced it
yet but they might wind up delaying shazam
two fury of the gods because they don't want to
compete with avatar two that disney is releasing
but if they delay that it'll probably just be
by a couple months like it won't be that long
and even though there is all the craziness with
ezra miller i've already done a video about that
because the flash series is ending basically
around the same time that they were originally
going to release the flash movie but if they delay
all the dc movies next year by a couple months
that's obviously going to change just a little bit
too the timing is a little bit weird like you end
the flash series and then you have the flash movie
like right after that is there going to be any
kind of cameo scene going on there there have been
reports that warner brothers does want to do more
with henry cavill and we talked about him cameoing
in the black adam movies because it sounds like
the rock really wants to do something with
him in the movies there have been all kinds of
rumors about that i don't know which are true and
which are false reportedly henry cavill has his
own plans for the future of superman and warner
brothers and him just can't come to an agreement
yet so a lot of that is still up in the air like
he could come back in cameos but he could also
really fully come back and do more full-blown
superman movies if we get any more information
about that in the next couple months of course
i'll release a video about it but i will do
more black adam trailer videos and easter eggs
for the movie as it slowly comes out there'll
be more trailers as we get a little bit closer
i'll post all my marvel trailers this weekend
just depending on whatever they wind up releasing
make sure you enable alerts for my channel so you
don't miss that my full house the dragon episode
4 video will post on sunday too click here for my
full house the dragon episode 4 trailer video
and click here for my video on all the brand
new scenes that they added to the spiderman no way
home extended version of the movie that they just
released thank you so much for watching everyone
stay safe and i'll see you guys in the next one!